# **CHRISTOPHER** CONI FY WEB DEVELOPER

### CONTACT

- ceconley4@gmail.com
- ceconley.github.io/personal-portfolio/
- **(**607)221-1961
- **♀** Greater Providence Area
- in linkedin.com/in/christopher-conley
- ceconley

### **SUMMARY**

My background is in leading large teams. I have worked for 2 Fortune 500 companies in the retail environment. This allowed me to fulfill 1 of my 2 main passions. I love working on teams of people with diverse perspectives. My other passion is using analytical thinking to solve complex technical problems. When I decided to branch out and expand my skills, I started with data analytics. This eventually led me to coding and web development. Now, every day I'm doing something love. Whether I'm building projects, fixing bugs or collaborating with my peers, the time just flies.

### **SKILLS**

WEB DEVELOPMENT

DATA ANALYSIS

HTML SOL Fxcel CSS Tableau JavaScript

**JOuery** AIAX Ruby Rails

PostgreSQL

Node.js Express

Mongo DB

SASS

Bootstrap

Handlebars

### **EDUCATION**

#### **DATA-NAVIGATORS**

Certificate Program Data Analysis and Visualization 2018 Providence Public Library

#### STATE UNIVERSITY OF NEW YORK -CORTLAND

B.S. Business Economics 2011

## **PROJECTS**

#### TIC TAC TOF

- -Built a single page web application from scratch, without a starter codebase.
- -Built to a spec that someone else gave me.
- -Used my programming skills to write a custom game engine for Tic Tac Toe.
- -Used AJAX to interact with a provided API, to create and store game states.
- -Future iterations will allow for multi-player/multi-device game-play.
- -Created documentation and practiced version control, file management and proper code styling.

Technologies Used: JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, HTML5, CSS3 and Bootstrap

#### **EXPENSE TRACKER**

- -Built an expense tracking, single-page application with basic user authentication.
- -The front-end interacts with a custom API.
- -The back-end was built using Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL.
- -This app allows a signed-in user to CRUD a PSQL database.
- -The user controls these actions on the front-end, along with the ability to organize and analyze the data returned.

Technologies Used: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX HTML5, CSS3 and Bootstrap and Handlebars

#### INVENTORY MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

- -First time working in a group environment as a developer.
- -The 4 group members all started at different levels of ability and understanding.
- -First day was spent creating a group culture-code and going through old code, to get on the same page.
- -One obstacles we ran into was Git workflow, but we were able to overcome them pretty easily. -Another issue was members not meeting deadlines, so we had to figure out how to pick up that slack.
- -Ultimately we met the MVP by the deadline.
- -The project was an Inventory Management System for an online retailer.
- -It was a full-stack, single page application, using Express and Mongo for the backend.

Technologies Used: Express.Js, MongoDB, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap and Handlebars

#### **DAILY FANTASY CHAMPS**

- -With my 2nd and 3rd projects being more business oriented, I wanted to have some fun with my 4th.
- -I enjoy playing daily fantasy sports, so I decided to make a fantasy football single page application.
- -This allows players to select from pre-made lineups and enter them in different contests.
- -There were 2 major challenges I put on myself for this project:
  - 1. Create 3 resources that all have a many-to-many relationship with each other.
  - 2. Design the UI so the user doesn't have to enter any data after they are logged in.

Technologies Used: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap and Handlebars

### **EMPLOYMENT**

#### GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Providence, RI 2018 to 2019

Web Development Fellow

I built 4 projects in an immersive, 12 week, 500+ hour, web development training program. We focused on utilizing modern full-stack programming languages, frameworks, version control, and agile methodology.

#### **SELF EMPLOYED** Commodity and Equity Derivatives Trader

East Greenwich, RI 2018 to Current

I managed a small fund, using learned trading methods and risk management strategies to generate profitable results.

#### **RETAIL MANAGEMENT**

General Manager

NY. CT. MA 2005 to 2018

For 13 years I was a Retail Manager for 2 Fortune 500 and 1 of Forbes Top Private Companies. I held roles ranging from Department Supervisor to Store Manager. During this time I led small and large teams and won multiple awards for Operations, Sales and Profit.

### WHAT'S NEXT

#### START TAKING AN ONLINE SCRUM COURSE

During my time at General Assembly, I started to research Scrum and Agile methodologies. We even used Scrum on our group project, where I acted as Scrum Master. Now I am going to take a course and earn the Certification.

### LEARN REACT AND BUILD A PROJECT

I have already started to learn React. The next step is to start building a project to further my learning. My plan for the project is an e-commerce site with shopping cart.

#### LEARN PYTHON AND BUILD A WEB SCRAPER

I have some fantasy football models that I maintain in Excel. It is a time consuming process to update the data from various sources every week. This was a good incentive to start learning Python, so I can build a web scraper to cut down the time it takes, while exploring all of the other opportunities it provides.